[
    {
        "question": "What is the correct way to declare an integer variable?",
        "answers": [
            "int x = 5;",
            "integer x = 5;",
            "num x = 5;",
            "var x = '5';"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What data type is suitable for a word?",
        "answers": [
            "int",
            "string",
            "bool",
            "float"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a boolean variable?",
        "answers": [
            "'1'",
            "'True'",
            "1",
            "True"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the type(5.5) command return in Python?",
        "answers": [
            "<class 'string'>",
            "<class 'int'>",
            "<class 'float'>",
            "<class 'double'>"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the data type of the value 'Hello'?",
        "answers": [
            "int",
            "float",
           "string",
            "bool"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct for storing a decimal number?",
        "answers": [
            "int x = 4.5;",
            "float x = 4.5;",
            "bool x = 4.5;",
            "string x =4.5;"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What data type is used to store logical values? ",
        "answers": [
            "int",
            "float",
            "bool",
            "char"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following variables is valid in Python?",
        "answers": [
            "1name = John",
            "_name = John" ,
            "name# = John",
            "if = John"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a mutable data type in Python?",
        "answers": [
             "tuple",
             "string",
             "int",
             "list"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the type(False) command return?",
        "answers": [
            "<class 'string'>",
            " <class 'int'>",
            "<class 'bool'>",
            "<class 'NoneType'>"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct way to declare a list?;",
        "answers": [
            "list = [1, 2, 3]",
            "list = {1, 2, 3}",
            "list = (1, 2, 3)",
            "list = 1, 2, 3"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum number of characters a string variable can store?",
        "answers": [
             "256",
             "1024",
             "There is no limit", 
             "64,000"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following values ​​is considered False?",
        "answers": [
              "str(False)",
              "0",
              "1",
              "str(0)"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commands converts an integer to a decimal number?",
        "answers": [
            "int(5.0)",
            "str(5)",
            "bool(5)",
            "float(5)" 
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following symbols is used for comments?",
        "answers": [
            "//",
            "#",
            "<!-- -->",
            "/* */"
        ],
        "correctAnswerIndex": 1
    }
]
